Guide to the Dorothy F. Regnery Papers, 1980-1991
Department of Special Collections
Dorothy F. Regnery Papers,
1980-1991
Special Collections M0479
Regnery, Dorothy F.
12 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Dorothy Regnery, 1988-1990, and David Regnery, 1991.
Biographical Note
Historian, particularly interested in central California and Stanford University.
Scope and Content
Research materials for several projects, including the Stanford's Sacramento house and the Jasper Ridge Biological Preserve history. Two research papers, "A study of the Leland Stanford House in Sacramento, California," 1987, and, "The Serra statue at Presidio Monterey," 1988. Included are house plans for the Hoover house and the Durand-Kirkman house at Stanford.
Container List
- Notebook: Baptismal record of St. Denis Church, 11/19/1855-9/15/1863. (Box 1, Folder NF)
- Loose-leaf Binder: St. Denis Church and Cemetery Records. (Box 1, Folder NF)
- Copies of Lou Henry Hoover Papers (1917- n.d.)on the Hoover House at Stanford (Hoover Library, West Branch IA: 1986). (Box 1, Folder NF)
- Misc. Architecture Books. (Box 1, Folder NF)
- Photgraphs and Negatives of details from: (Box 2, Folder NF)
  - -Durand-Kirkman House
  - -Twin House to Griffen-Drell House
  - -Griffen-Drell House
  - -Dunn-Bacon House
  - -Winery/The Barn
  - -The Quad/Stanford Chapel
  - -Memorial Church
- Information on Hopkins Room, Hopkins Table. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Research materials on Serra Statue (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Campus Cemetery: Old Graves on Stanford Campus; Copies of Supporting Documents, Brd. of Trustees 1913/1914. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Horse Statue at Palo Alto Stock Farm (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Horse Statue research (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Research: San Francisco House and Washington D.C. House of the Stanfords. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Leland Stanford-- Personal: Copies of Late 19th Century and Early 20th Century Newspaper Articles. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- San Juan Hill: History of houses, including copies of plans for interior details of Durand House. Photos encl. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Cedro Cottage: Articles, correspondance. Photos enclosed. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Griffen-Dushane-Drell House: Map, Photos enclosed. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Clelia Duel Mosher, M.D.: Research and Information. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- McFarland House. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Cooksey House. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Hanna Honeycomb House: National Register Materials. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Mrs. Hoover's Seven Low-Income Houses. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- President's Houses: Xasmin, Serra. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- A.B. Clark (Includes newspaper clippings). (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Bakewell and Brown Duplexes. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- The Knoll/President's House. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Row and Early Houses. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Dunn-Bacon House (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Stanford/Palo Alto Winery/Barn. (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Arguello Land. (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Grist Mill Information. (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Martin Ranch. (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Catholic Church Role: Alemany, etc. Early Peninsula Churches. (Box 3, Folder 18)
- St. Denis Church: Misc. Notes. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Mills owned by the Martin family. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Other Martins. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- John Martin (Brother of Dennis, Dublin) (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Indian Jim Martin. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Correspondance, Interviews. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Martin-- News reports, pre-1900. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- _____, 1900-1940. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- _____, 1940-1949. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- _____, 1950-1959. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Exhumation of Martin Cemetary. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Martin-- News reports, 1960-1969. (Box 4, Folder 12)
- _____, 1970-1979. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Martin materials, 1982. (Box 4, Folder 14)
- St. Denis Church: Ledgers, correspondence (copies). (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Church Membership. (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Stevens-Murphy Party. (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Stanford Zoology Club/Jasper Ridge Information. (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Stanford Linear Accelerator (SLAC) articles. (Box 4, Folder 19)
- SLAC. (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Shack Riders, Trail Club Newsletters. (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Searsville. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Murray, John. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Spaulding, Joseph Stillman, Jr. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Peers, Alexander amd Elizabeth Ann Boynton (Photos encl.) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Peers relatives. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Peers: Interviews, Letters. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Hughes, William. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Coats, James and Mary Coats (who remarried to John Owens). (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Mills, John and John Franklin. (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Murphy, Rufus Norris and Delia Langan Murphy. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Plummer, Merrill and Agnes Murphy Plummer. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Boynton Family. (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Templeton, Horace. (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Sears, John Howell and Charles Bowers Sears. (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Eikerenkotter, Augustus Ike (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Photographs: Searsville Exchange, Searsville Hotel. (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Lloyd, William. (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Page, William H. (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Walsh (Welsh? Welch?) (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Davis, Moses and William Maxfield; Davis and Maxfield Searsville Hotel. (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Shine, Boyd, Little, and Snively (Photos encl.) (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Murphy, John; O'Keefe. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Prebble; Langan (Photos encl.) (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Residents of Searsville (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Searsville (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Searsville: Maps. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Photographs: Searsville and its Residents. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Searsville Post Office: Corresp. enclosed (1880-1890's). (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Searsville Lake: Water, SVWW, Resevoir. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Searsville Dam (Photos encl.) (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Searsville Lake (After 1919). (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Manzanita Water Company. (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Spring Valley Water Works (SVWW). (Box 6, Folder 13)
- SVWW: Portola Resevoir. (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Searsville Vicinity: Skipper's Park, Post-resevoir. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Searsville Resort. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Los Trancos Water Company. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Mountain Home Water Company. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Searsville Water Company. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Cortemadera Water Company, Menlo Park Water Company, Bear Gulch Water Company, California Water Service Company. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- SVWW. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Crystal Springs Dam (Photos encl.) (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Larcos, Nicholas. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Larco, Nicola. Barriolhet. (Biographical information). (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Silk-- Mulberry Orchards. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Ravetto, Leon: Correspondance. (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Mining by Larco, et al. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Grosso, Domingo/Dominico/Domenico: The Hermit. (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Grosso (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Domingo (Photos encl.) (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Jasper Ridge. (Box 7, Folder 17)
- _____. (Box 7, Folder 18)
- _____: Books, Histories, Accounts. (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Martin, Dennis. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- St. Denis Cemetery. (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Grave Markers (Martin lands, St. Denis Church). (Box 8, Folder 3)
- St. Dennis [sic.] (Martin) Church. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Martin Ranch Site (Photos encl.) (Box 8, Folder 5)
- St. Denis Church (Photos encl.) (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Stanford, Gordon, and Coutts. (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Gordon. (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Stanford Family (Photos encl). (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Stanford Family (Photos encl). (Box 8, Folder 10)
- The Quad. (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Hoover Heights in Oakland. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Loose-leaf Binder: Ts. of Book? The Peninsula Comes of Age (Photos Encl.). (Box 9, Folder NF)
- Public Positions and Honors: A Hoover Institution Pamphlet commemorating Herbert Hoover's 90th Birthday (?), 1964. (Box 9, Folder NF)
- Hoover House (photos encl.) (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Hoover House: Nat'l Landmark Materials. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Book: General Hoover Materials. (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Virtues: Oil Paintings belonging to Lou Hoover. (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Hoover House: Landmark and Register Materials and Information. (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Loose-leaf Binder: Hoover House, Ts. and materials (Photos encl.) (Box 9, Folder NF)
- Envelope: Coutts Trivia. (Box 10, Folder NF)
- Envelope: Coutts, Primary Sources. (Box 10, Folder NF)
- Coutts Tower: Point of Historical Interest Materials. (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Published Mss.: Stanford Historical Society Newsletters containing articles on Coutts. (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Bilson: Article on Coutts, 1962. (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Pallette: Article on Coutts. (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Kriss: Research on Coutts, 1965. (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Interviews. (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Mason, Nancy (Preservation of Coutts Library). (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Peter Coutts Hill: Condominium developments (newspaper clippings enclosed). (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Peter Coutts Hill: Floor plans. (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Buttery Dedication. (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Talks Given by Dorothy F. Regnery. (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Coutts Information: pre-1900. (Box 10, Folder 12)
- _____: 1900-1929. (Box 10, Folder 13)
- _____: 1930-1939. (Box 10, Folder 14)
- _____: 1940-1949. (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Coutts Information: 1950-1959. (Box 10, Folder 16)
- _____: 1960-1969. (Box 10, Folder 17)
- _____: 1970-1979. (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Maps. (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Photograph Captions (NO photos encl.) (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Deaths. (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Berlin, Marguerite. (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Bank Associations. (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Paul, William. (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Ayershire Dairy. (Box 10, Folder 25)
- Library. (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Little Nonsense. (Box 10, Folder 27)
- Photographs: Peter Coutts-related Sites (France, Library, Escondite Cottage, Tower, Ayershire Farm, Foothills). (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Ts. The Real Peter Coutts. (Box 11, Folder NF)
- American Ambulance Field Service at Stanford (AFS at Stanford). (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Misc. notes; The Czar's visit to Stanford. (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Records, St. Denis Church (copies). (Box 12, Folder 1)
- _____. (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Framptonian-American Information. (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Framptonian Trees (Geneological Information). (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Martin, Dennis and descendants. (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Unedited Manuscript of the History of Jasper Ridge. (Box 13)
- Daily Palo Alto Times, 1919-1920. (Box 14, Folder (OS))
- Palo Alto Live Oak: September 1897, 1 January 1900, June 1903. (Box 14, Folder (OS))
- Photographs and Prints.